Mubashir Siddiqui

QA Engineer

Karachi - PK ● mmubashir6@hotmail.co.uk ● +923348800240 ● linkedin.com/in/mubashirsiddiquii ● mubashirsiddiqui.github.io

Summary

An Experienced technologist in quality assurance, quality control and goal oriented, I am seeking a challenging opportunity to manage and lead large projects where my advanced skills, education, extensive training and many years of experience can be fully utilized.

Skills -

SQA | AGILE | JIRA | Azure | Scrum | API Testing | SQL | UAT | STLC | SDET | Manual Testing | Automation Testing | JMeter | Postman | Selenium | TestNG | Java | Selenium | Appium | Cypress | Slack | Trello | Project Management | Training & Development | Report Writing | MS Office

Professional Experience-

Decagon Pakistan Pvt. Ltd (Golootlo Technologies)

Senior SQA Engineer

Karachi, Pakistan

July 2021 - Present

- Collaborated closely with cross-functional teams, identifying and reporting software defects for timely resolution, maintaining quality standards, and achieving 30% cost savings through automation.
- Extensively engaged in test case creation by reviewing FSDs, providing feedback and recommendations for software improvement.
- Lead QA team of 4 different applications (Golootlo Consumer, Golootlo Merchant, Golootlo Operation and P2M) simultaneously with a total user base of over 3.5 million.
- Led the integration and management of 3rd-party payment systems and subscription models, streamlining financial transactions and enhancing user experience.

Decagon Pakistan Pvt. Ltd

SQA Engineer

Karachi. Pakistan

November 2019 - June 2021

- Conducted functional and non-functional testing of web-based applications and software solutions to ensure they meet user requirements and industry standards. Effectively carried out manual and automated testing including iOS and android applications, ensuring the highest level of quality and user satisfaction.
- Extensively engaged in test case creation by reviewing FSDs, providing feedback and recommendations for software improvement.
- Identified several loopholes in architecture after joining that resulted in 99.6% of crash-free users.

Binary Revolutions Pvt. Ltd

Karachi, Pakistan

Software Engineer in Test (Remote)

August 2020 – January 2021

- Implemented scripted functionality to generate monographs for the Ministry of Health application (KSA), resulting in a 50% reduction in deployment time.
- Provided 100+ bug reports with detailed descriptions to development teams

RIKSOF Pvt. Ltd Karachi, Pakistan

SQA Automation Engineer

March 2019 - September 2019

- Automation of web and desktop applications which increased velocity in testing team by 20% within 2 months
- Executed load and stress testing using JMeter, identifying performance bottlenecks and optimizing system.

Oventum Technologies

Karachi, Pakistan

Odoo Developer & SQA Engineer

December 2016 - February 2019

- Responsible for testing mobile and web applications manually with testcases and reporting
- Developed and tested Odoo addons, projects, products, and interfaces, guaranteeing seamless functionality.
- Provided customer support and guidance on Odoo module functionality.

Education -

NED University of Engineering and Technology

Master of Science in Computer Science and Information Technology

Karachi, Pakistan

2021 - 2022

University of Karachi

Bachelors of Science in Computer Science

Karachi, Pakistan 2014 - 2017